import { ref } from 'vue';
import { Learn } from './Learn';

export const U3_1 = ref<Learn[]>([
    { question: 'oh!, oi!', answer: 'Ach!' },
    { question: 'ahaa!', answer: 'Aha!' },
    { question: 'baar', answer: 'Bar, die -s' },
    { question: 'näide', answer: 'Beispiel, das, -e' },
    { question: 'kirjeldama', answer: 'beschreiben' },
    { question: 'sest, kuna', answer: 'denn' },
    { question: 'taani keel', answer: 'Dänisch, das' },
    { question: 'natukene', answer: 'etwas (= ein bisschen)' },
    { question: 'euroopa', answer: 'Europa (das)' },
    { question: 'sõitma', answer: 'fahren' },
    { question: 'soome keel', answer: 'Finnisch, das' },
    { question: 'võõrkeel', answer: 'Fremdsprache, die, -n' },
    { question: 'meelsasti, hea meelega', answer: 'gern' },
    { question: 'eile', answer: 'gestern' },
    { question: 'graafika', answer: 'Grafik, die, -en' },
    { question: 'piir', answer: 'Grenze, die, -n' },
    { question: 'kreeka keel', answer: 'Griechisch, das' },
    { question: 'tervitus', answer: 'Gruß, der, "-e' },
    { question: 'pealinn', answer: 'Hauptstadt, die, "-e' },
    { question: 'informatsioon', answer: 'Information, die, -en' }
]);

export const U3_2 = ref<Learn[]>([
    { question: 'itaalia keel', answer: 'Italienisch, das' },
    { question: 'iga; igaüks', answer: 'jeder, jede (f.), jedes (n.)' },
    { question: 'kaart', answer: 'Karte, die, -n' },
    { question: 'kontakt, kokkupuude, ühendus', answer: 'Kontakt, der, -e' },
    { question: 'maakaart', answer: 'Landkarte, die, -n' },
    { question: 'lamama; asuma', answer: 'liegen' },
    { question: 'kord; korraks', answer: 'mal' },
    { question: '-kse', answer: 'man' },
    { question: 'rohkem (kui)', answer: 'mehr (als)' },
    { question: 'emakeel', answer: 'Muttersprache, die, -n' },
    { question: 'naaber', answer: 'Nachbar, der, -n' },
    { question: 'naabrimaa', answer: 'Nachbarland, das, "-er' },
    { question: 'hollandi keel', answer: 'Niederländisch, das' },
    { question: 'põhi, põhjakaar', answer: 'Norden, der' },
    { question: 'põhja pool', answer: 'nördlich von' },
    { question: 'vaid, ainult', answer: 'nur' },
    { question: 'koht, paik', answer: 'Ort, der, -e' },
    { question: 'ida', answer: 'Osten, der' },
    { question: 'juhtuma', answer: 'passieren' },
    { question: 'portugali keel', answer: 'Portugiesisch, das' }
]);

export const U3_3 = ref<Learn[]>([
    { question: 'postkaart', answer: 'Postkarte, die, -n' },
    { question: 'projekt', answer: 'Projekt, das, -e' },
    { question: 'reegel', answer: 'Regel, die, -n' },
    { question: 'regioon, ala, piirkond', answer: 'Region, die, -en' },
    { question: 'juba', answer: 'schon' },
    { question: 'rootsi keel', answer: 'Schwedisch, das' },
    { question: 'vaatamisväärsus', answer: 'Sehenswürdigkeit, die, -en' },
    { question: 'väga', answer: 'sehr' },
    { question: 'slovaki keel', answer: 'Slowakisch, das' },
    { question: 'nii', answer: 'so' },
    { question: 'seisma', answer: 'stehen' },
    { question: 'lõuna', answer: 'Süden, der' },
    { question: 'päev', answer: 'Tag, der, -e' },
    { question: 'tšehhi keel', answer: 'Tschechisch, das' },
    { question: 'üle; peal', answer: 'über' },
    { question: 'erinevus, vahe', answer: 'Unterschied, der, -e' },
    { question: 'võrdlema', answer: 'vergleichen' },
    { question: 'liiklus', answer: 'Verkehr, der' },
    { question: 'palju', answer: 'viele' },
    { question: 'vahetama', answer: 'wechseln' },
    { question: 'lääs', answer: 'Westen, der' },
    { question: 'Kuidas läheb?', answer: "Wie geht's?" }
]);